[{"stepName": "Identify Motion of objects", "stepNumber": 1, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many moving objects are present?", "options": [1, 4, 5, 2], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": -1, "show1": [""], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082"], "showfc": [], "type": "basic", "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block", "stepNumber": 2, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "How many surfaces are in contact with the red block?", "options": [5, 1, 2, 0], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -200, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "answer": 2, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to B?", "options": ["N1 perpendicular up", "N1 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "answer": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to b2?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "answer": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "answer": 0}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block along the incline?", "options": ["30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, "], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2081+N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081+N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082+30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 3, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081"], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N1, N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 30cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 30sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Red block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "How many surfaces are in contact with the yellow block?", "options": [5, 0, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -200, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "answer": 2, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to b1?", "options": ["N2 perpendicular up", "N2 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 1, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "answer": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 2 due to B?", "options": ["N3 perpendicular up", "N3 perpendicular down"], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 2, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "answer": 0, "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"]}, {"question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for yellow block cuts the strings", "options": [0, 1, 2, 3], "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": -100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic", "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: ", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: "], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "answer": 0}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block along the incline?", "options": ["50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "-0sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "type": "basic"}, {"question": "Whats the FBD equation of yellow block perpendicular to the incline?", "options": ["+N\u2082+N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083+50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "+N\u2082-N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "fbd", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": 100, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082"], "showfc": ["Upward Perpendicular Forces: N2, N3, ", "Downward Perpendicular Forces: 50cos(45\u00b0)", "Forces up the incline: ", "Forces down the incline: 50sin(45\u00b0)"], "showfcheading": ["Yellow block"], "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "type": "basic"}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Understanding", "stepNumber": 3, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards right with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 1, "threejssubsubstep": [0, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards left with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 2, "threejssubsubstep": [0, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards right with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 3, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards left with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 4, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 0], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 5, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 6, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-8, 8, 2, -2], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 7, "threejssubsubstep": [3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 2m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 8, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [-3, 3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 9, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, 8, -8, -2], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 10, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, 5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 8m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [5, -5], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 11, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 12, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, -8, 8], "answer": 2, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 13, "threejssubsubstep": [3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -8m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s", "options": [-5, 5], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 14, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": [], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [3, -3], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 15, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}, {"question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s", "options": [2, -2, 8, -8], "answer": 1, "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding", "threejssubstep": 16, "threejssubsubstep": [-3, -5], "show1": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"], "show2": ["Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s", "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s", "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -2m/s"], "type": "basic", "showfc": [], "showfcheading": []}]}, {"stepName": "Constraint Equations", "stepNumber": 4, "stepQuestions": []}, {"stepName": "Final Answers", "stepNumber": 5, "stepQuestions": [{"question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?", "options": ["a\u2081= -7.07, a\u2082= -7.07, N\u2081= 21.13, N\u2083= 35.21", "a\u2081= -21.13, a\u2082= -35.21, N\u2081= 7.07, N\u2083= 7.07", "a\u2081= 7.07, a\u2082= 7.07, N\u2081= -21.13, N\u2083= -35.21", "a\u2081= 7.07, a\u2082= 7.07, N\u2081= -35.21, N\u2083= -21.13"], "answer": 0, "threejsstep": "motion", "threejssubstep": 0, "threejssubsubstep": 0, "show1": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0"], "showfc": [], "showfcheading": [], "tobeshown": 1, "show2": ["Unknowns: a\u2081, a\u2082, ", "Red block: 30sin(45\u00b0)=3a\u2081", "Red block: +N\u2081-N\u2082-30cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Yellow block: 50sin(45\u00b0)=5a\u2082", "Yellow block: +N\u2082+N\u2083-50cos(45\u00b0)=0", "Final Answers: a\u2081= -7.07, a\u2082= -7.07, N\u2081= 21.13, N\u2083= 35.21"]}]}]